<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Joan Tolos</title>
    <link>http://www.joantolos.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Joan Tolos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.joantolos.com/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The road to digital redemption</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/the_road_to_digital_redemption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/the_road_to_digital_redemption/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is forever. I am going to use an example of the comedy industry to illustrate the point of this post, but it can be extrapolated to any aspect of life. Comedy has been always a risky business in the sense of offending people and going &amp;ldquo;over the line&amp;rdquo;, it is actually part of the skill, to know when to push and when to pull back. If we take a look at old comedy movies or acts, we are going to see and hear stuff that sounds really offensive to our modern eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iteration over repetition</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/iteration_over_repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/iteration_over_repetition/</guid>
      <description>Let’s explore the difference between repetition and iteration. When you repeat something, you are doing the same thing several times. When you iterate over something you are building over the previous outcome. Let’s choose the proper tool (repetition or iteration) wisely.
Agile example One example that we may found familiar is the concept of agile development. The whole point is to deliver working software (remember: working software over documentation ) so we can listen to the feedback early on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict resolution tip</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/conflict_solving_tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/conflict_solving_tip/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with a conflict at work, you want to reach a win-win situation where both parts are satisfied. Some other quick solutions, like just voting among the team, still leaves a winner and a loser even if the process has been “just” or at least consensual with all the team. This kind of situations, can grow resentment among the members of the team and can create a big price to pay in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social network case study</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/social_network_case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/social_network_case_study/</guid>
      <description>A naive experiment: I have been publishing a lot lately into two social networks: Twitter and Linkedin. The idea was to see how a lot of activity would impact in the relevance of my profiles. In order to do that, first I compiled a long list of publications composed by my own blog posts, so I just had to copy/paste into the platforms.
The only criteria was to just publish every day, no other consideration like time of the day or kind of publication was considered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Either lead, follow or get out of the way</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/either_lead_follow_or_get_out_of_the_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/either_lead_follow_or_get_out_of_the_way/</guid>
      <description>Lead, follow or get out of the way is a phrase widely used, specially on military context. It&amp;rsquo;s attributed to several people: Thomas Paine (American political activist, philosopher), general Patton or even leaders of civil industries. I want to talk about it in the context of a software creation team.
Committed or involved It is often used on the agile community a reference to the business fable of the chicken and the pig , sometimes represented with a cartoon like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days of isolation</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/lockdown/</guid>
      <description>As the world is facing the pandemic caused by this new Coronavirus strain, most of my colleagues and myself are forced to work from home. I want to share my experience working without leaving the house.
Particular circumstances I want to point out that this is not just &amp;ldquo;working from home&amp;rdquo;, these are extreme circumstances.
In my case, the most defining one is the fact that the schools are closed. That means that my two kids (which are four and two) have to be with my wife and myself at home and due to their ages, we can not leave them alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My brief experience as team lead</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/teamlead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/teamlead/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity of take over my manager role for a brief period of time due to his parenting absence. I was doing it kind of informally when he was on vacation or had a sick day or something. This time it was for a longer and delimited period so we kind of &amp;ldquo;formalised&amp;rdquo; the whole thing.
I have to say, this time, I was really happy coding and had a very nice plan for the year (this role change was happening on January) and I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the new responsibility with a lot of enthusiasm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running on fumes</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/fumes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/fumes/</guid>
      <description>It is desirable to be physically healthy. When we are out of shape we suffer the consequences rapidly and we want to abandon that situation as soon as possible and regain our health.
We also see the benefits of being not only healthy but fit. The main difference between healthy and fit that I want to use for make the point of this post is:
When you are healthy, you are ok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action bias</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/actionbias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/actionbias/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a simple task: we want to go to the venue of the next conference by walking. We have the essential skill to achieve the goal, we know how to walk. So we go down the street and start walking going around the block over and over. Then we ask ourselves why we never arrive to the place. Ring any bell?
Our perceptions are sometimes deceiving because movement is perceived as progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The imposter syndrome</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/imposter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/imposter/</guid>
      <description>I was talking with an ex peer some time ago. We were talking about taking new chances and moving on from one job to another. I told him that sometimes I feel like I am asking too much and I have doubts of my potential. Then he told me that this is called the imposter syndrome and that it happens to him as well. That was the first time I heard the expression, then I started to take a look and research a little bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The real reason why you don&#39;t like TDD</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/tddcasestudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/tddcasestudy/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever read somebody&amp;rsquo;s code and thought: &amp;ldquo;that is just beautiful, I wish I could code like this&amp;rdquo;? The answer is simple: nobody codes like this at first attempt. Good code is always the result of several refactoring, iterations, reviews and improvements. Most of the time made by more than one person.
So the goal as developers should be to write the best code that we can. In order to do that we should consider has many tools and techniques as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Extreme Leadership</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/extremeownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/extremeownership/</guid>
      <description>Extreme leadership is a book by Jocko Willink and Leif Babin about how U.S. Navy SEALs lead and win.
The premise of this book is very interesting. The authors are two former Navy SEALs:
The navy SEALs are the U.S. Navy&amp;rsquo;s primary special operations force and a component of the Naval Special Warfare Command. Among the SEALs&amp;rsquo; main functions are conducting small-unit maritime military operations that originate from, and return to, a river, ocean, swamp, delta, or coastline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quick fix society</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/quickfix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/quickfix/</guid>
      <description>Uber, Netflix, Spotify, fast food&amp;hellip; As the song said&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;We want it all and we want it now.&amp;quot; But, is it now always the right time? Can everything we need, be packed into a five minutes digested pills?
I recently stumbled upon an article explaining the techniques behind a good headline. These days it looks like social media interactions are starting to have a bad reputation, so it is hip to abandon them or hide over the most used catch phrase &amp;ldquo;I just read articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I do it?</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/doit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/doit/</guid>
      <description>From time to time somebody ask me how do I do it meaning, how I manage to do all the things that I do besides the normal activity of work and family.
Here the things that I do on my spare time:
 Read books Write blog posts Play guitar Work on my pet project Exercise  So people ask me, how I have the time to do that things. As if somebody can have time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>