<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refactoring on Joan Tolos</title>
    <link>http://www.joantolos.com/categories/refactoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refactoring on Joan Tolos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.joantolos.com/categories/refactoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The real reason why you don&#39;t like TDD</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/tddcasestudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/tddcasestudy/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever read somebody&amp;rsquo;s code and thought: &amp;ldquo;that is just beautiful, I wish I could code like this&amp;rdquo;? The answer is simple: nobody codes like this at first attempt. Good code is always the result of several refactoring, iterations, reviews and improvements. Most of the time made by more than one person.
So the goal as developers should be to write the best code that we can. In order to do that we should consider has many tools and techniques as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One task to rule them all</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/gradletask/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/gradletask/</guid>
      <description>Trying to learn a little bit more about how Gradle deals with tasks and how to execute them in an specific order.
The problem I was asked for help on a project dealing with Gradle task and what is seemed like a simple ordering task problem. The set up is the following:

This is a simplification of the project layout, where names have been changed. We have a module that creates files and another module that consumes the files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code that should not be</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/thecodethatshouldnotbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/thecodethatshouldnotbe/</guid>
      <description>Some thoughts about the amount of code you write that never see production and how to take it.
The context We were asked to implement a new feature, let&amp;rsquo;s say, selling apples. Not groceries, not fruits, just apples. Well, maybe on the next Sprint we will add bananas to sell as well. But that&amp;rsquo;s it, apples now and bananas later.
We all love to code for lists instead of instances, so the coder assigned to the task designed a beautiful code supporting a whole list of fruits, even it was clear from the start that business just needed apples for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readability</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/readability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/readability/</guid>
      <description>Less is more&amp;hellip; but really? I always struggle to find an example where less code is not necessarily better, because it usually is. But recently I stumble upon an example. Clean Code ask for readability over anything else because code is more often read than written. That sometimes may mean to be a little more verbose on the code. Let&amp;rsquo;s see an example:
The context I have to paint a simple plot, x and y axis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>