<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Joan Tolos</title>
    <link>http://www.joantolos.com/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Joan Tolos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.joantolos.com/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to sort and paginate your table with Typescript</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/tablemanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/tablemanager/</guid>
      <description>You should always delegate your sorting and pagination needs to the data retriever engine that you are using. For example, if it is a classical relational database you should use ORDER BY, OFFSET, FETCH, LIMIT and whatever mechanisms you have available. Same thing with NoSQL databases. These things are designed to perform well when asking for this kind of sorting and pagination features. So, you should always go for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 tools to help you do TDD with NodeJS</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/javascripttrifecta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/javascripttrifecta/</guid>
      <description>I am using NodeJS more and more to implement middleware services instead of Java. That means that I am dealing with Javascript on a daily basis. In order to add features with guaranties, I code with TDD ( and only TDD ) and that means that I need a few tools to code comfortably:
 Some BDD or asserting framework Some Code Coverage framework ( I use code coverage to inspire refactors ) Some mocking device  Mocha  Mocha is a feature-rich JavaScript test framework running on Node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>