<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ethics on Joan Tolos</title>
    <link>http://www.joantolos.com/categories/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ethics on Joan Tolos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.joantolos.com/categories/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The road to digital redemption</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/the_road_to_digital_redemption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/the_road_to_digital_redemption/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is forever. I am going to use an example of the comedy industry to illustrate the point of this post, but it can be extrapolated to any aspect of life. Comedy has been always a risky business in the sense of offending people and going &amp;ldquo;over the line&amp;rdquo;, it is actually part of the skill, to know when to push and when to pull back. If we take a look at old comedy movies or acts, we are going to see and hear stuff that sounds really offensive to our modern eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iteration over repetition</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/iteration_over_repetition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/iteration_over_repetition/</guid>
      <description>Let’s explore the difference between repetition and iteration. When you repeat something, you are doing the same thing several times. When you iterate over something you are building over the previous outcome. Let’s choose the proper tool (repetition or iteration) wisely.
Agile example One example that we may found familiar is the concept of agile development. The whole point is to deliver working software (remember: working software over documentation ) so we can listen to the feedback early on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conflict resolution tip</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/conflict_solving_tip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/conflict_solving_tip/</guid>
      <description>When dealing with a conflict at work, you want to reach a win-win situation where both parts are satisfied. Some other quick solutions, like just voting among the team, still leaves a winner and a loser even if the process has been “just” or at least consensual with all the team. This kind of situations, can grow resentment among the members of the team and can create a big price to pay in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social network case study</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/social_network_case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/social_network_case_study/</guid>
      <description>A naive experiment: I have been publishing a lot lately into two social networks: Twitter and Linkedin. The idea was to see how a lot of activity would impact in the relevance of my profiles. In order to do that, first I compiled a long list of publications composed by my own blog posts, so I just had to copy/paste into the platforms.
The only criteria was to just publish every day, no other consideration like time of the day or kind of publication was considered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days of isolation</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/lockdown/</guid>
      <description>As the world is facing the pandemic caused by this new Coronavirus strain, most of my colleagues and myself are forced to work from home. I want to share my experience working without leaving the house.
Particular circumstances I want to point out that this is not just &amp;ldquo;working from home&amp;rdquo;, these are extreme circumstances.
In my case, the most defining one is the fact that the schools are closed. That means that my two kids (which are four and two) have to be with my wife and myself at home and due to their ages, we can not leave them alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My brief experience as team lead</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/teamlead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/teamlead/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity of take over my manager role for a brief period of time due to his parenting absence. I was doing it kind of informally when he was on vacation or had a sick day or something. This time it was for a longer and delimited period so we kind of &amp;ldquo;formalised&amp;rdquo; the whole thing.
I have to say, this time, I was really happy coding and had a very nice plan for the year (this role change was happening on January) and I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the new responsibility with a lot of enthusiasm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on Extreme Leadership</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/extremeownership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/extremeownership/</guid>
      <description>Extreme leadership is a book by Jocko Willink and Leif Babin about how U.S. Navy SEALs lead and win.
The premise of this book is very interesting. The authors are two former Navy SEALs:
The navy SEALs are the U.S. Navy&amp;rsquo;s primary special operations force and a component of the Naval Special Warfare Command. Among the SEALs&amp;rsquo; main functions are conducting small-unit maritime military operations that originate from, and return to, a river, ocean, swamp, delta, or coastline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quick fix society</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/quickfix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/quickfix/</guid>
      <description>Uber, Netflix, Spotify, fast food&amp;hellip; As the song said&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;We want it all and we want it now.&amp;quot; But, is it now always the right time? Can everything we need, be packed into a five minutes digested pills?
I recently stumbled upon an article explaining the techniques behind a good headline. These days it looks like social media interactions are starting to have a bad reputation, so it is hip to abandon them or hide over the most used catch phrase &amp;ldquo;I just read articles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do you hate your job?</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/hatejob/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/hatejob/</guid>
      <description>“Between 2011 and 2012 the polling company Gallup conducted the most detailed study ever carried out of how people across the world feel about their work. They studied millions of workers across 142 countries. They found that 13 percent of people say they are engaged in their jobs, which means they are &amp;lsquo;enthusiastic about, and committed to their work and contribute to their organisation in a positive manner.&amp;rsquo; Against them, 63 percent say they are not engaged, which is defined as &amp;lsquo;sleepwalking through their workday, putting time (but not energy or passion) into their work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The code that should not be</title>
      <link>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/thecodethatshouldnotbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.joantolos.com/blog/thecodethatshouldnotbe/</guid>
      <description>Some thoughts about the amount of code you write that never see production and how to take it.
The context We were asked to implement a new feature, let&amp;rsquo;s say, selling apples. Not groceries, not fruits, just apples. Well, maybe on the next Sprint we will add bananas to sell as well. But that&amp;rsquo;s it, apples now and bananas later.
We all love to code for lists instead of instances, so the coder assigned to the task designed a beautiful code supporting a whole list of fruits, even it was clear from the start that business just needed apples for now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>